Jamil Vallis-Walker

Web, Salesforce, & Software Developer

LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

Education

Berkeley Coding Bootcamp

UC Berkeley Extension
JUN 2024 - DEC 2024

Over the course of six months, I learned / completed the following:

- Built front-end websites from scratch, as well as used ready-made frameworks
- Created full-stack single-page web applications using RESTful API routes and AJAX methods
- Developed an understanding of how front-end applications communicate with back-end applications and databases.
- Implemented structured and unstructured databases to convert static websites into dynamic websites that persist data.
- Lead group projects as a Project Manager, implementing and training teammates on source control best practices, as well as handling application design and code reviews.
- Expanded my coding capability to include Javascript, React, Node.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, and GraphQL, in addition to my existing skills in Python and Apex (Java)

B.A in Psychology San Jose State University 2010 - 2013

About

Ever since discovering Excel formulas in my first job out of college, building applications has fascinated me. Although I lacked formal training, I quickly learned and became an Apex (Java) Developer after being introduced to the Salesforce ecosystem.

I've spent the past 5+ years deepening my understanding of coding principles, and recently completed a Full Stack bootcamp through UC Berkeley Extension. I'm excited to take this next step in my career into the world of full stack web development.

Experience

Salesforce Developer // SambaSafety

AUG 2023 - Present

- Develop Apex for record trigger automations and lwc/action functionality
- Develop python scripts for populating complex CPQ data in sandbox and production environments
- Lead initiative to transition Salesforce org to international currency quoting capability

Salesforce Developer // Lyra Health

OCT 2021 - JAN 2023

- Core member of development and support team (Apex, LWCs, Org-to-Org and Vendor-to-Org integration)
- Developed git/source-control solutions for expanding development team

Salesforce Developer // Making Waves Foundation MAR 2019 - OCT 2021

- Sole member of development and support team (Apex, LWC, declarative programming, Lightning transition)
- Lifecycle management of all Salesforce projects (requirement gathering, development, UAT/QA, and post-launch support)

Salesforce Administrator // Making Waves FoundationSEP 2017 - MAR 2019

- Develop new Salesforce functionality in collaboration with interdepartmental staff via org configuration and declarative programming
- Perform prg maintenance, such as system updates, backups, data import and exports